SRI KORITALA

Learning Technology Officer

Address: 8/445Anzac Highway, Camden Park, Adelaide, South Australia 5038 Phone: +61 435536261 | Email: chanduk0406@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

IT Desktop Support Engineer with 5.5 years of experience working in the IT industry. I hold a master's degree in Information Technology from Federation University, Australia. I strive to produce the best customer satisfaction, ensuring the customer needs have been met. My edge is understanding the various stages and processes involved in ITIL. My strengths include customer service, troubleshooting technical issues, root cause analysis, building and rebuilding computers, documenting technical knowledge, problem-solving, communication, and great attention to detail. Working well together with clients, I am friendly, supportive, and helpful. I enjoy taking on the responsibility of training team members and contributing to problem-solving initiatives. I am thorough, organized, patient, and focused with attention to detail and process follow-through.

S		

- Highly developed written and oral communication
- Hardware and Network Troubleshooting
- Mobile device troubleshooting
- Root cause analysis
- Software Troubleshooting
- Install and Support Windows OS and macOS
- Extensive knowledge in IT Service Management

Tools: Salesforce, ServiceNow, and Service

Desk

Manage Engine

- Good knowledge of Active Directory and
- Good knowledge of Microsoft 365
 administration
- Good knowledge of Cisco WebEx

- Highly developed knowledge in IT service management
- · Highly developed skills in Ticket management
- Good knowledge of Microsoft Intune
- Good knowledge of networking protocols (TCP/IP,

DNS, DHCP)

- Good knowledge of PureCloud and Telstra call center Administration
- Programming languages: JavaScript.
- Web technologies: HTML, CSS
- Databases: MySQL
- Scripting: PowerShell
- Knowledge of React Framework
- Good understanding of web server environments

EXPERIENCE

Learning Technology Officer | July 2021 - Present

Department For Education | Adelaide, SA, Australia

- First point of contact for answering technical inquiries.
- Use remote tools such as TeamViewer to diagnose and resolve technical issues effectively.
- Provide support and setup Audio Visual equipment.
- Monitor the service desk's daily performance, utilizing service metrics to identify trends and potential opportunities for improvement.
- Contribute to continuous process improvement of the Service Desk and the development of online self-help tools.
- Work collaboratively with other members of the Learning Technology Team to ensure consistent, effective, and customer-focused service delivery.
- Contribute to and encourage the adoption of innovative learning technologies by providing ongoing education and support to the teachers, including developing selfhelp resources, training materials, and facilitating workshops.
- Provide technical advice concerning addressing ICT-related problems across the college.
- Proactively testing equipment, including the imaging of laptops for staff and student use.
- Contribute to continuous process improvement of all related service delivery processes.
- Undertake cross-functional services in support of the broader Ancillary Team.
- Contribute to continuous process improvement of all client service delivery functions across teams.

Desktop Support Specialist | August 2020 – July 2021

Smartgroup Corporation | Adelaide, SA, Australia

- Assist staff via phone, email, service desk request, in person, and remotely.
- Take ownership of tickets.
- Track, monitor, follow up and escalate incidents to appropriate groups to resolve the issue promptly.
- Actively review and resolve helpdesk requests raised by businesses focusing on root cause resolution.
- Assist in the development and maintenance of standard operating processes and procedures.
- Develop and maintain key internal and external relationships, including liaising with stakeholders on policy, project, or operational issues and responding to stakeholder needs and expectations.
- Coordinate with team members and other IT support departments to provide resolution of issues, including escalation of more complex issues to management and technical teams as required.
- Troubleshoot and configure Citrix Workspace/Global Protect VPN.

- Build and deploy operating systems to windows laptops using Microsoft Intune.
- Administer, troubleshoot, and configure MS Office 365 for staff.
- Support service delivery and infrastructure team to achieve high service uptime by providing information and updates regarding system performance and outages.
- Manage hardware asset registers to ensure manageable stock levels.

IT Service Desk Analyst | February 2020-July 2020

Department for Education | Adelaide, SA, Australia

- Handled all incoming queries and help requests from end users via phone and email.
- Ask end-users targeted questions to understand the root of the problem quickly.
- Troubleshoot and resolve level 1 technical issues remotely using LogMeIn.
- Organise and manage user accounts, computers, and other OUs in Active Directory Manager.
- Log all calls and queries using ServiceNow.
- Track issues logged through ServiceNow and provide updates to end-users.
- Escalate unresolved issues to appropriate level 3 groups and vendors.
- Follow up with end-users to ensure their IT systems are fully functional after troubleshooting.

IT Onsite Support Engineer | July 2018- February 2020

Williams Sale Partnership | Adelaide, SA, Australia

- First point of contact to troubleshoot issues with Windows 10 operating systems.
- Image and re-image laptops.
- Ask customers targeted questions to understand the root of the problem quickly.
- Supported users with hardware troubleshooting and software installations.
- Troubleshoot hardware equipment and perform initial repairs.
- Troubleshoot and resolve issues with network printers.
- Researched and identified solutions to software and hardware issues.
- Ensure all issues are logged adequately in ServiceNow and escalated unresolved issues to appropriate level 3
 groups and vendors.
- Audit hardware equipment configured and delivered new hardware equipment as per organizational standards.
- Follow up with clients to ensure the IT systems replaced are fully functional.
- Verify stock levels of supplies and request new inventory to meet service levels.
- Performed move/add/changes in local office; performed asset disposal and liaised with the vendor to schedule pick-ups.
- Written and documented technical knowledge in the form of notes and manuals.

IT Desktop Support Engineer | October 2016- June 2018

NBNCo | Adelaide, SA, Australia

- Troubleshoot and fix level 1 incidents.
- Provide technical support on Windows Operating system issues.
- Resolve technical issues on-site, by phone, and by email.
- Install & support new applications on laptops.
- Troubleshoot and replace the faulty hardware.
- Setup new hardware whenever and wherever requested by the client.
- Log and monitor all new jobs using the Salesforce help desk ticketing system.
- Escalate tickets to service providers and level 3 support groups which cannot be resolved on-site.
- Create and manage user accounts, computers, and other OUs in Active Directory Manager.
- Provide Office 365 support to users.

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp Certificate | March 2020 University of Adelaide | Adelaide, SA, Australia

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL.

Master of Information Technology | July 2016

Federation University | Adelaide, SA, Australia

Bachelor of Computer Science | November 2010

SRM University | Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

CERTIFICATIONS

1. AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals

REFERENCES

Referee 1

Name: Kylee Fenwick Position: Business leader

Organisation: Department for Education, South Australia.

Email: Kylee.Fenwick259@schools.sa.edu.au

Referee 2

Name: Mitul Patel

Position: Senior Desktop Support Engineer **Organisation**: Smartgroup Corporation, Australia.

Email: Mitul370@gmail.com

Referee 3

Name: Zayd Broocha

Position: Service Delivery Lead

Organisation: Smartgroup Corporation, Australia.

Email: Zaydb083@gmail.com